Guide to the Jesse Isidor Straus Autograph Collection, approximately 1727-1873
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Jesse Isidor Straus Autograph Collection
approximately 1727-1873
Straus, Jesse Isidor
0.8 cubic feet (3 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Letters, notes, receipts, dispatches, and some facsimile reproductions of documents pertaining to political and cultural events of the 18th and 19th centuries, including the French Revolution. Signers include Holy Roman Emperor Charles VI, Johann Gottfried Von Herder, Helmuth Graf von Moltke, Mozart, Jean Paul Richter, August Wilhelm von Schlegel, Johann Strauss, and Robert Walpole.
Scope and Content Note
Letters, notes, receipts, dispatches, and some facsimile reproductions of documents pertaining to political and cultural events of the 18th and 19th centuries, including the French Revolution. Signers include Holy Roman Emperor Charles VI, Johann Gottfried Von Herder, Helmuth Graf von Moltke, Mozart, Jean Paul Richter, August Wilhelm von Schlegel, Johann Strauss, and Robert Walpole.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Names:
Charles VI, Holy Roman Emperor, 1685-1740; Herder, Johann Gottfried, 1744-1803; Moltke, Helmuth, Graf von, 1800-1891; Jean Paul, 1763-1825; Schlegel, August Wilhelm von, 1767-1845; Strauss, Johann; Walpole, Robert, Earl of Orford, 1676-1745; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Richter, Jean Paul, 1763-1825
Places:
Europe--Social life and customs; Europe--Politics and government; France--History--Revolution, 1789
Document Types:
Autographs
VCL Categories:
Autographs
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, August 2007. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, September 2025.
Custodial History
The materials in this collection were gathered by Jessi Isidor Straus, the U.S. ambassador to France (1933-1936) and grandfather of Barbara Levy, VC 1942.
Acquisition Information
Barbara Levy donated the bulk of the material in 1939 when she was a freshman at Vassar. She gave a second smaller accession in January 1945 (marked with an asterisk in the container list). The gifts originally formed part of the Lucy Maynard Salmon Collection of Historical Materials.
Arrangement
Arranged by country. The items from the 1945 accession are marked with an asterisk (*).
Series List
- Series I. France
- Series II. Germanies
- Series III. Great Britain
- Series IV. Scandinavia
- Series V. Italy
- Series VI. United States
- Series VII. Miscellaneous
Container List
- I. FRANCE
  - IA. Before 1789
    - Anne, Duc de montmorency, 1493-1567 — Document dealing with landed estates, 1562 Jun 1; [oversize] (Box 3, I.A1)
    - Henry IV, King of France, 1553-1610 — Letter to the Count Palatine of the Rhine (Box 1, I.A2)
    - Turenne, Henri de la Tour d’Auvergne vicomte de, 1611-1675 — Letter to Cardinal Mazarin, 1658 (Box 1, I.A3)
    - Moritz, Graaf von Sachsen, 1696-1750 (Saxe, Hermann-Maurice, comte de) — Document, 1729 (Box 1, I.A4)
    - Necker, Jacques, 1732-1804 — Order, 1780 Mar (Box 1, I.A5)
    - Malesherbes, Chrétien Guillaume de Lamoignon de 1721-1794 — Letter, 1787 Jan (Box 1, I.A6)
    - Letter signed L.P.T. d’Orleans, Paris, 1786 (Box 1, *I.A7)
  - IB. 1789-1799
    - Augereau, Prince Françios Charles, duc de Castiglione, 1757-1816 — Letter, 8 Thermidor year II, 1794 Jul 26 (Box 1, I.B1)
    - Barère de Vieuzac, Bertrand, 1755-1841 (other names on document) — Committee of Public Safety 17 Messidor of year II, 1794 Jul 5 (Box 1, I.B2)
    - Barras, Paul François Jean Nicolas, 1755-1829 (other names on document not all identified) — Committee of General Security, 18 Brumaire Year III, 1794 Nov 8 (Box 1, I.B3)
    - Beauharnais, Alexandre, 1760-1794 (other names on document not all identified) — National Assembly, 1791 Aug 7 (Box 1, I.B4)
    - Billuad-Varenne, Jean Nicolas, 1756-1819 — See Barère (I.B5)
    - Cambacères, Jean Jacques Régis, duc de 1753-1824 (another name on document) — Committee of Public Safety, 21 Pluviôse Year III, 1795 Feb 9 (Box 1, I.B6)
    - Carnot, Lazare Nicoas Marguerite 1753-1823 (other names on document) — Committee of Public Safety, 5 Ventôse Year II, 1794 Feb 23 (Box 1, I.B7)
    - Chabot, François, 1759-1794 — Declaration of income, 1793 (Box 1, I.B8)
    - Chaumette, Pierre Gaspard, 1763-1794 (in folder with Cambacères) — Commune of Paris, 13 Brumaire Year II, 1793 Nov 3 (Box 1, I.B9)
    - Collot d’Herbois, Jean Marie, 1750-1796 — See Barère and Carnot (I.B10)
    - Guillotin, Joseph Ignace, 1738-1814 — Letter, 1813 Mar 12 (Box 1, I.B11)
    - Jourdan, Jean Baptiste, comte, 1762-1833 — Official military letter, 16 Thermidor Year II, 1794 Aug 3 (Box 1, I.B12)
    - Laignelot, Joseph François, 1752-1829 — See Barras (Box 1, I.B13)
    - Lindet, R. ? Two brothers with Robert as part of name Lindet, Jean Baptiste Robert, 1746-1825 Lindet, Robert Thomas, 1743-1823 See Barère and Carnot (Box 1, I.B14)
    - Marie Antoinette, 1755-1793 — Order, [1781 Jan 2?]; [2 folders] (Box 1, I.B15)
    - Méaulle, Jean Nicolas, 1757-1824 — See Barras (I.B16)
    - Merlin de Douai, Philippe Antoine, 1754-1838 — See Cambacères (I.B17)
    - Mirabeau, Honoré Gabriel Vicot Riqueti, comte de, 1749-1791 — Letter, 1779 Oct 15 (Box 1, I.B18)
    - Moreau, Jean Victor, 1763-1813 — Letter, undated (Box 1, I.B19)
    - Moreaux, Jean René, 1758-1795 — See Tallien (I.B20)
    - Nogaret, Jacques Ramel, 1760-1819 — See Beauhrnais (I.B21)
    - Reverchon, Jacques, 1746-1828 — See Barras (I.B22)
    - Rouget de Lisle, Claude Joseph, 1760-1836 — Composition? And letter, 1831 May 8 (Box 1, I.B23)
    - Tallien, Jean Lambert, 1767-1820 — Committee of Public Safety, 16 Florial Year III, 1795 May 5 (Box 1, I.B24)
  - IC. 1799-1815 (Napoleonic Era)
    - Arrighi, Jean Toussaint, duc de Padoue, 1778-1853 — Letter, 1810 Apr 21 (Box 1, I.C1)
    - Bernadotte, Jean Baptiste Jules, 1764-1844 (later Charles XIV of Sweden and Norway) — Ministry of War, 8 Fructidor Year VII, 1800 Aug 26 (Box 1, I.C2a)
    - Bernadotte, Jean Baptiste Jules, 1764-1844 (later Charles XIV of Sweden and Norway) — Letter, 1814 Oct 1 (Box 1, I.C2b)
    - Berthier, Louis Alexandre, 1753-1815 — Ministry of war, 21 Prairial Year XI, 1803 Jun 10 (Box 1, I.C3)
    - Bertrand, Henri Gratien, 1773-1844 — Letter, 1827 Jan 10 (Box 1, I.C4)
    - Bessières, Jean Baptiste, duc d’Istrie, 1766-1813 (Another signature on letter) — Letter, 1811 (Box 1, I.C5)
    - Boissy d’Anglas, François Antoine, comte de, 1755-1826 — Letter, 1824 Jan 23 (Box 1, I.C6)
    - Brune, Guillaume Marie Anne, 1763-1815 — Official notice, 1807 Oct 26 (Box 1, I.C7)
    - Caffarelli (five brothers?) Louis M.J.M, 1756-1799; C.A., 1758-1826; L.M.J., 1760-1845; J.B., 1763-1815; F.M.A., 1766-1849 — See Lannes (Box 1, I.C8)
    - Davout, Louis Nicolas, duc d’Auerstaedt prince d’Eckműhl, 1770-1823 — Military document, ll Pluviôse Year X, 1802 Jan 31 (Box 1, I.C9)
    - Duroc, Géraud Christophe Michel, duc de Frioul, 1772-1813 — See Bessières (I.C10a)
    - Duroc, Géraud Christophe Michel, duc de Frioul, 1772-1813 — Letter, 1811 Feb 17 (Box 1, I.C10b)
    - Fouché, Joseph, duc d’Ortranto, 1759-1820 — Ministry of the General Police 5 Florial Year VIII, 1800 Apr 25 (Box 1, I.C11)
    - Gouvion St. Cyr, Laurent, marquis de, 1764-1830 — Ministry of War, 1818 Jun 13 (Box 1, I.C12)
    - Grouchy, Emmanuel, marquis de 1766-1847 — Ministry or war-receipt, 1814 Dec [19?] (Box 1, I.C13)
    - Josephine Bonaparte, 1763-1814 — Letter, undated (Box 1, I.C14)
    - Junot, Andoche, duc d’Abrantes, 1771-1813 — Ministry of War-reciept, 1806 Sep 30 (Box 1, I.C15)
    - Kellermann, François Christophe, duc de Valmy, 1735-1820 — Legion of Honor, 1812 Jan [29?] (Box 1, I.C16)
    - Lannes, Jean, duc de Montebello, prince de Siévers, 1769-1809 (several other names not all identified) — Financial record of consular guard, 7 Frimaire year IX, 1800 Nov 28 (Box 1, I.C17)
    - Lefebvre, Francois Joseph, duc de Dantzig, 1755-1820 — Notice of military promotion, 13 Brumaire Year XIV, 1805 Nov 4 (Box 1, I.C18)
    - Macdonald, Jacques Etienne Joseph Alexander, duc de Tarente, 1765-1840 — Royal Order of Legion of Honor, 1818 Jun 8 (Box 1, I.C19)
    - Marmont, Auguste Frédéric Louis Viesse de, duc de Raguse, 1774-1852 — Royal and Military Order of St. Louis, [1819 Mar 19?] (Box 1, I.C20)
    - Mars, Anne, F.H.B., Mlle, 1779-1847 — Letter, undated (Box 1, I.C21)
    - Masséna, André, duc de Rivoli, prince d’Essling, 1756-1817 — Ministry of war-receipt, 1811 Aug 28 (Box 1, I.C22)
    - Moncey, Bon Adrien Jeannot de, duc de Conegliano, 1754-1842 — Official letter from office of the Imperial Guard, 1813 Feb 17 (Box 1, I.C23)
    - Mortier, Edouard Adolphe Casimir Joseph,duc de Trévisee, 1768-1835 — Royal Order of the Legion of Honor, 1833 May 11 (Box 1, I.C24)
    - Murat, Joachim, 1771-1815 — Note, undated (Box 1, I.C25)
    - Napoleon I, 1769-1821 — Imperial Passport, 1812 Oct 9 (Box 1, I.C26)
    - Ney, Michel, duc d’Elchingen, 1769-1815 — Official military letter, 16 Prairial year X, 1802 Jun 5 (Box 1, I.C27)
    - Ordener, Michel, comte, 1755-1811 — See Lannes (Box 1, I.C28)
    - Oudinot, Nicolas Charles, duc de Reggio, 1767-1847 — Army of Italy, letter, 19 Messidor, year VIII, 1800 Jul 8 (Box 1, I.C29)
    - Perignon, Dominique Catherine de 1754-1818 — Letter, 1817 Mar 13 (Box 1, I.C30)
    - Poniatowski, Joseph Antoine, prince, 1762-1813 — Document, 1808; [oversize] (Box 3, I.C31)
    - Sérurier, Jean Mathieu Philibert, 1742-1819 (Another name not identified on document) — Letter, undated (Box 1, I.C32)
    - Soult, Nicolas Jean de Dieu, duc de Dalmatie, 1769-1851 — Letter, 1835 Apr 2 (Box 1, I.C33)
    - Stael-Holstein, Anne L.G. Necker, baronne de, 1766-1817 — Letter, undated (Box 1, I.C34)
    - Suchet, Louis Gabriel, duc de D’Albufera, 1772-1826 — Letter, 1817 Jul 17 (Box 1, I.C35)
    - Talleyrand-Périgord, Charles Maurice de, 1754-1838 — Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 9 Vendémiaire, Year VI, 1797 Sep 30 (Box 1, I.C36)
    - Talma, François Joseph, 1763-1826 — Letter, undated (Box 1, I.C37)
    - Victor, Claude Victor Perrin dit, duc der Bellune, 1766-1841 — Letter, 1808 Mar 3 (Box 1, I.C38)
  - ID. 1815-1900
    - Dejazet, Pauline Virginie, 1797-1875 — Letter, undated (Box 1, I.D1)
    - Dumas, Alezandre (invitation connected with Dumas Père, but no evidence to prove whether the letter is Père or Fils) Père, 1803-1870 Fils, 1824-1895 — Two items: formal invitation, And a letter, [1865?], undated (Box 1, I.D2)
    - Pélissier, Aimable jean Jacques, duc de Malakof, 1794-1864 — Card with signature, undated (Box 1, I.D3)
    - Rachel Felix, Elizabeth, 1820-1858 — Letter, [1847 Jun 12?] (Box 1, I.D4)
    - Trochu, Louis Jules,1815-1896 — Letter, 1864 Jan 3 (Box 1, I.D5)
    - Uhrich, Jean Jacques Alexis, 1802-1886 — Army of Italy, Letter, 1860 Apr 6 (Box 1, I.D6)
    - Letter from Napoleon III on embossed note of paper, dated Tuileries, [1865 Jan 5?] (Box 1, *I.D7)
- II. THE GERMANIES
  - IIA. The Hapsburgs
    - Alva, Fernando Alvarez de Toledo, 1508-1583 — Order, 1572 Mar (Box 1, II.A1)
    - Wallenstein, Albrecht Eusebius Wenzel von, Herzog von Friedland and Mecklenburg, 1583-1634 — Seal, 1630 Aug 27 (Box 1, II.A2)
    - Charles VI, 1685-1740 — Seal, [1727?]; [2 folders] (Box 1, II.A3)
    - Marie Therese, 1717-1780 — Letter to the Bishop of Wurzburg and Bamberg, undated (Box 1, II.A4)
    - Joseph II, 1741-1790 — Imperial decree, 1783 Oct 20; [oversize] (Box 3, II.A5)
    - Hofer, Andreas, 1767-1810 — Letter, 1809 Mar 5 (Box 1, II.A6)
    - Laudon or Loudon, Johann Ludwig Alexius, Freiherr von, 1762-1822 — Letter, 1811 Aug [16?] (Box 1, II.A7)
    - Radetsky, Joseph, 1766-1858 — Letter, 1822 Apr 20 (Box 1, II.A8)
    - Francis Joseph I, 1830-1916 — Note, undated; [2 folders] (Box 1, II.A9)
    - Maximilian, Emperor of Mexico, 1832-1867 — Official letter, 1866 Nov 28; [oversize] (Box 3, II.A10)
    - Rauscher, Joseph Othmar, Fursterz-bischof von Wien and Kardinal, 1797-1875 — Signature, [1876?] (Box 1, II.A11)
  - IIB. Prussia
    - Louise, Queen of Prussia, 1776-1810 — Letter, undated (Box 1, II.B1)
    - Blucher, Gebhard Leberrecht von, 1742-1819 — Letter, 1815 Oct 16 (Box 1, II.B2)
    - Bismarck Schőnhausen, Karl Otto, Furst von, 1815-1898 (another signature on the document) — Note and envelope, undated (Box 1, II.B3)
    - Bucher, Lothar, 1817-1892 — See Bismarck, undated (Box 1, II.B4)
    - Moltke, Helmuth, Graf von, 1800-1891 — Series of notes, one of them with the signature of von Moltke. Others not identified, 1872 (Box 1, II.B5a)
    - Moltke, Helmuth, Graf von, 1800-1891 — Note, 1873; [2 folders] (Box 1, II.B5b)
    - Roon, Albrecht, Graf von, 1803-1879 — Letter, 1870 Aug 23 (Box 1, II.B6)
    - Werder, August von, 1808-1887 — Letter, [1863 or 1873] Nov 28 (Box 1, II.B7)
  - IIC. German Culture - German enlightenment
    - Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1749-1832 — Letter, 1812 Mar [17?] (Box 1, II.C1)
    - Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1749-1832 — Letter, 1829 (Box 1, II.C1)
    - Herder, Johann Gottfried von, 1744-1803 — Letter, [1796 Apr 16?]; [3 folders] (Box 1, II.C2)
    - Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859 — Letter, 1832 Oct (Box 1, II.C3)
    - Kant, Immanuel, 1724-1804 — Letter, 1800 Feb [7?] (Box 1, II.C4)
    - Klopstock, Friedrich Gottlieb, 1724-1803 — Letter, 1748 Jul 11 (Box 1, II.C5)
    - Schiller, Johann Christoph Friedrich von, 1759-1805 — Letter, undated (Box 1, II.C6)
    - Wieland, Christopher Martin, 1733-1813 — Letter, 1802 Nov 3 (Box 1, II.C7)
    - Letter signed "Neuber", a receipt for payment. Miss Luckau thinks signature at left of document is by Goethe, undated (Box 1, *II.C8)
  - IID. German Culture - The Romantics
    - Grimm, Jacob, 1785-1863 — Letter, 1828 Apr [7?] (Box 1, II.D1)
    - Grimm, Wilhelm Carl, 1786-1859 — Letter, 1807 Jun 27 (Box 1, II.D2)
    - Richter, Jean Paul Friedrich, 1763-1825 — Letter, 1812 Dec [8?] (Box 1, II.D3a)
    - Richter, Jean Paul Friedrich, 1763-1825 — Letter, undated; [2 folders] (Box 1, II.D3b)
    - Ruckert, Friedrich, 1788-1866 — Letter, undated (Box 1, II.D4)
    - Schlegel, August Wilhelmvvon, 1767-1845 — Letter, undated (Box 1, II.D5)
    - Schlegel, Friedrich von, 1772-1829 — Letter, 1801 Nov [3?] (Box 1, II.D6)
    - Schleiermacher, Friedrich Ernst Daniel, 1768-1834 — Letter, 1809 Nov 9; [2 folders] (Box 1, II.D7)
    - Uhland, Ludwig, 1787-1862 — Letter, 1846 Oct 13 (Box 1, II.D8)
  - IIE. German culture - Later Nineteenth Century
    - Auerbach, Berthold, 1812-1882 — Letter, 1861 Jul 27 (Box 1, II.E1)
    - Dingelstedt, Franz, Freiherr von, 1814-1881 — Letter, 1846 Jun 14 (Box 1, II.E2)
    - Dőllinger, Ignaz von, 1799-1890 — Letter, 1876 Apr 14 (Box 1, II.E3)
    - Gerstacker, Friedrich, 1816-1872 — Letter, 1869 May 20 (Box 1, II.E4)
    - Grillparzer, Franz, 1791-1872 — Distich, 1857 Oct 25 (Box 1, II.E5)
    - Hacklander, Friedrich Wilhelm, 1816-1877 — Letter, 1856 Mar [7?] (Box 1, II.E6)
    - Heinsius, Theodor H. 1770-1849 — Letter, 1840 Oct 11 (Box 1, II.E7)
    - Laube, Heinrich, 1806-1884 — Letter, 1848 Dec 28 (Box 1, II.E8)
    - Mommsen, Theodor, 1817-1903 — Letter, 1856 May 24 (Box 1, II.E9)
    - Mosenthal, Salomon Hermann, Ritter von, 1821-1877 — Letter, 1857 (Box 1, II.E10)
    - Virchow Rudolf, 1821-1902 — Letter, 1847 Apr 15 (Box 1, II.E11)
  - IIF. Music
    - Abt, Franz, 1819-1885 — Letter, 1866 Dec 18 (Box 2, II.F1)
    - Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809 — Letter, [1788 May 22?] (Box 2, II.F2)
    - Pleyel, Ignaz, 1757-1831 — Letter, 1804 Jul 1 (Box 2, II.F3)
    - Spohr, Louis, 1784-1859 — Letter, undated (Box 2, II.F4)
    - Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899 — Waltz, 1854 Mar 11; [2 folders] (Box 2, II.F5)
    - Weber, Karl Maria von, 1786-1826 — Note, [1812 Feb 3?]; [2 folders] (Box 2, II.F6)
    - Letter signed by Mozart, 1782, inviting Baroness Waldstetter to his house for "beer in the English manner,", 1782 Oct 2; [3 folders] (Box 2, *II.F7)
  - IIG. Drama, dancing, singing, etc.
    - Elssler, Fanny, 1810-1884 — Note, undated (Box 2, II.G1)
    - Janauschek, Fanny, 1830-1904 — Letter, undated (Box 2, II.G2)
    - Lucca, Pauline, 1841-1908 — Letter, undated (Box 2, II.G3)
    - Montez, Lola, Grafin von Landsfeld, 1818-1861 — Note, undated (Box 2, II.G4)
    - Seebach, Marie, 1829-1897 — Two letters, 1864 Feb 18 and 1898 Nov 5 (Box 2, II.G5)
    - Sontag, Henriette, Countess Rossi, 1806-1854 — Letter, undated (Box 2, II.G6)
  - IIH. Art
    - Kaulbach, Wilhelm, 1805-1874 — Letter, undated (Box 2, II.H1)
    - Klenze, Franz Karl Leo von, 1784-1864 — Letter, 1832 May 12 (Box 2, II.H2)
    - Schwanthaler, Ludwig von, 1802-1848 — Letter, [1841?] (Box 2, II.H3)
- III. GREAT BRITAIN
  - Churchill, John, first Duke of Marlborough, 1650-1722 — Proclamation to the army, 1703 Jul 11 (Box 2, III.1)
  - Ruys (not identified) — Letter written at the Hague, Holland,telling of the arrival of George II en route to Hanover. In French, 1755 Apr 30 (Box 2, III.2)
  - Charlotte Sophia, Queen of George III, 1744-1818 — Signature, 1772 (Box 2, III.3)
  - Wellesley, Arthur, Duke of Wellington, 1769-1852 — Letter, 1843 Apr 18 (Box 2, III.4)
  - Acton, John Emerich Edward Dalberg, first baron, 1834-1902 — Letter and envelope, [1875 Jun 17?] (Box 2, III.5)
  - Buchanan, Andrew, 1807-1882 — Letter, 1873 Jul [29?] (Box 2, III.6)
  - Fragment of letter to George, Earl of Halifax, signed by Walpole, George Doddington and George Oxenden, 1730 (Box 2, *III.7)
- IV. SCANDINAVIA
  - Bremer, Frederika, 1801-1865 — Letter, 1845 Mar 13 (Box 2, IV.1)
  - Thorvaldsen, Albert, 1770-1844 — Receipt, 1842 May 27 (Box 2, IV.2)
- V. ITALY
  - Canova, Antonio, marquis of Ischivia, 1757-1822 — Letter, 1817 Oct 30 (Box 2, V.1)
  - Pius IX, 1792-1878 — See Rauscher (II.A11), [1876?] (V.2)
  - Ristori, Adelaide, 1822-1906 — Two items: Poem and letter, 1858 Mar 12 and 1863 Jul 22 (Box 2, V.3)
  - Taglioni, Marie T. 1804-1884 — Note, undated (Box 2, V.4)
- VI. UNITED STATES
  - Letter from Matthew Carey, with reply from John Thompson at the end of the letter., undated (Box 2, *VI.1)
  - Paper money, State of Massachusetts Bay, $4.00, May, 1780 (Box 2, *VI.2)
  - Autograph of Lincoln, apparently clipped from a letter, 26 October 1864, 1864 Oct 26 (Box 2, *VI.3)
  - Autograph of Jefferson Davis on a calling card., undated (Box 2, *VI.4)
  - Autograph of Benjamin Harrison on a card with engraved view of White House (?), undated (Box 2, *VI.5)
  - Autograph of Grover Cleveland on a calling card, 1885 Aug 31 (Box 2, *VI.6)
  - Envelope of seals clipped from documents, American Legation in St. Petersburg, etc., undated (Box 2, *VI.7)
- VII. MISCELLANEOUS
  - Louise, Queen of Belgium,1812-1850 (Louise d’Orleans) — Letter, 1847 Nov 22 (Box 2, VII.1)
  - Kauffman, Angelica, 1741-1807 (Swiss) — Letter, 1792 Sep 8 (Box 2, VII.2)
  - Caroline (Dealer has identified the signature as the Queen of Bavaria. Place and date under signature are Munich. At this time the Queen of Bavaria was Wilhelmine Auguste, wife of Maximilian I. Other queens of German origin by this name circa 1811 were: Caroline Amelie, of England, 1768-1821; Caroline Amelie of Denmark, 1796-1881; Marie Caroline of Naples, 1752-1814), 1811 Nov 18 (Box 2, VII.3)